<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<doc>
    <p>DRAFT -- DRAFT -- DRAFT!</p>
    <strong>Obstacles finding complex NPP data</strong>
    <p>The study of long term patterns in primary production is one of the core research areas at
        every LTER site, and a typically reported measurement is “net primary production” (NPP),
        e.g., the amount of new organic material produced in a time interval. Each LTER site’s
        measurements of NPP are determined locally and depend on the organisms being studied, e.g.,
        their sizes, growth rates and community composition, and so methods vary widely in scope
        (organism, community, ecosystem), and in temporal and spatial scales. Methods also have
        different assumptions and limitations. It can be difficult to ascertain if any groups of NPP
        values are comparable without knowing these significant details. Scientists conducting
        synthesis projects using LTER data need a) to accurately find data sets containing NPP with
        the appropriate dimensions, and b) to learn enough about the methods in different studies to
        evaluate compatibility with their needs (Figure 1).</p>
    <p>To enhance all data searches, the LTER information managers designed a SKOS-based controlled
        vocabulary. Through its use of “narrower terms” and “synonyms”, this has helped to refine
        search results in the Network catalog. But because the vocabulary’s scope is very broad, the
        NPP-related terms number fewer than 20 and there are essentially no terms related to field
        methods. A data collection as complex as LTER NPP data would be better served by an
        ontological system having strong semantic relationships and expressivity. The development of
        such a system is not possible with our current resources. Additionally, the issues
        surrounding description of NPP data are not unique to LTER, and the most complete, robust
        solution will be developed by a collaboration of data scientists and informatics specialists
        from many communities.</p>
    <table>
        <tbody>
            <tr>
                <td colspan="2">Figure 1. Methods for measuring NPP at LTER sites may have significant differences in temporal and spatial scales. Left, a chamber for measuring in situ NPP in a benthic algal community at the Santa Barbara Coastal LTER. Right, satellite image of NPP from the BigFoot site, Harvard Forest (image downloaded from ORNL DAAC).</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <td>
                    <p>
                        <img src="/sites/databits.lternet.edu/files/large_benthicNPPchamber400.jpg"
                            alt="Chamber for measuring in situ algal NPP at SBC"
                            title="Chamber for measuring in situ benthic algal community NPP at SBC"
                            width="180" height="180"/>
                    </p>
                </td>
                <td>
                    <p>
                        <img
                            src="/sites/databits.lternet.edu/files/large_BigFoot_NPP_Site_Harvard_Forest_LTER_MA_USA_2003_courtesy_ORNL_DAAC.png"
                            alt="NPP from the BigFoot site, Harvard Forest (image downloaded from ORNL DAAC)"
                            width="180" height="180"/>
                    </p>
                </td>
            </tr>
        </tbody>
    </table>


    <img/>
    <p>INSERT photo Caption: 2 photos: 1) SBC benthic O2 chamber, 2) that ornl daac image of harvard
        forest.</p>
    <strong>Enter DataONE</strong>
    <p>The DataONE project began in 2009 and its large and diverse group of scientists and software
        engineers now coordinates hundreds of thousands of datasets from a diverse group of member
        nodes. LTER joined in 2012, contributing about 9000 records. Having recently entered Phase
        II, DataONE’s mission now includes solving specific problems for the earth science
        community. Its investigators are well aware of the difficulties that scientists face during
        data discovery, and plan cyberinfrastructure that will incorporate innovative and high-value
        features - among them, semantic technologies to enable precise data discovery and recall
        with measurement searches.To develop ontological solutions for data discovery, DataONE must
        begin with a “use case”, a sample problem which is constrained in scope, but complex enough
        to present a variety of potential obstacles, and with a large corpus of data with rich
        metadata. LTER’s diverse primary production data is an ideal case for testing semantic
        searches. </p>
    <p>Our range of measurements, biomes, and methodologies, comprising approximately 2500 datasets
        will ensure multiple benefits: <ul>
            <li>DataONE is able to compare the effectiveness of an array of approaches</li>
            <li>LTER has a solution for one of its more complex data types</li>
            <li>The modeling patterns employed will be extensive enough to accommodate other future
                work in other scientific domains</li>
        </ul></p>
    <strong>Implementation plan</strong>
    <p>Broadly speaking, two major new components are needed for this semantic system: the ontology
        itself (also called a “knowledge model”), and the annotation to link datasets to concepts in
        the ontology. Many concomitant issues have been identified, particularly related to
        involvement with the the scientific community, including versioning, ownership, and design
        and usability of web-interfaces. All new technology is planned to build on pre-existing
        community practices for ontology and annotation formats and management. A working product is
        planned to be ready early in 2016, with a session planned for the 2015 LTER ASM to gather
        feedback on progress to date.</p>
    <p>A group evaluated the current landscape of knowledge modeling for NPP data and ascertained
        that there were no pre-existing comprehensive models for this scientific domain. And so,
        DataONE’s work will serve not just its own and LTER’s needs, but the greater NPP community
        as well. One important activity will be an “annotation experiment” to compare precision and
        recall for datasets with no annotation (e.g., the current text search), with manual
        annotation, fully automated annotation (based on text and unit matching algorithm), and
        semi-automated annotation (auto with additional choice/verification by users).</p>
    <p>DataONE has already dedicated a developer with an extensive background in coding for semantic
        systems. A computer science postdoc works on text and unit-matching algorithms. An LTER
        information manager acts as a coordinator, along with informatics scientists who have
        created other ontological frameworks. Under this group’s direction, two graduate students
        working at UC Santa Barbara/NCEAS will work on various aspects of assembly and annotation. </p>
    <strong>Extensions, relationship to other DataONE efforts</strong>
    <p>In addition to semantic search, DataONE also is implementing a system to enhance
        reproducibility by storing and indexing provenance trace information. The use case for this
        provenance work is the Multi-scale Synthesis and Terrestrial Model Intercomparison Project
        (MsTMIP), a comparison of carbon flux model results and observations, whose overall goal is
        to provide feedback to the terrestrial biospheric modeling community to improve the
        diagnosis and attribution of carbon sources and sinks. MsTMIP’s central measurement is Net
        Ecosystem Exchange (NEE), and MsTMIP has identified contributing measurements which are
        comparable to many LTER measurements, e.g., NPP.</p>
    <p>MsTMIP needs differ from those of LTER. Because the MsTMIP project is concerned with model
        results, its needs are primarily to track data provenance, and data discovery issues are
        secondary. However, scientists using MsTMIP data will need to: a) know which MsTMIP-model
        produced the dataset, and b) find appropriate benchmark data for model evaluation.
        Developing semantic structures for carbon flux should meet the discovery needs of both
        projects.</p>
    <p>An initial focus on NPP data serves an important and timely need for the LTER, while setting
        the stage for future work. For example, continuing with the same projects, an extension
        could model and annotate the MsTMIP models themselves, which would also provide general
        examples for handling and modeling provenance. Another possibility is to improve discovery
        for data related to other carbon-cycling processes, e.g., oceanic carbonate system
        parameters for the study of ocean acidification. That work would almost certainly involve a
        broad community that intersected the LTER. Alternatively, we could tackle measurements in
        another LTER core research area. Nutrient flux is timely to consider because the Science
        Council plans to address this topic in upcoming synthesis projects. Semantic web
        technologies are an active area of development with high potential. But we know from our own
        experience that our data are too diverse to tackle at one time. We will be best served by
        breaking it into manageable chunks, and leveraging the work of those whose missions
        complement our own.</p>
</doc>
